Finding Aid for Center for Middle Eastern and North African Studies (University of Michigan) Publications, 1961-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Center for Middle Eastern and North African Studies (University of Michigan) Publications 1961-1997
University of Michigan. Center for Middle Eastern and North African Studies.
1.8 linear ft.
Interdisciplinary area studies center at the University of Michigan. Publications miscellaneous annual reports, brochures, calendars, catalogs listing scholarly publications from the center, flyers, and newsletters which describe the activities of the faculty and students. Also includes publications from the Curriculum Development Group, Middle East Outreach Council, and the Middle East Studies Association of North America.
9925 Bimu 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the unit (donor # 8554).
The records are open for research.
See the History at the beginning of finding aid for the record group Center for Middle Eastern and North African Studies (University of Michigan) Records
The Center's publications are divided into three series: Unit Publications, Sub-Unit Publications, and Topical Publications.
Unit Publications includes the Center's annual reports, some research reports in three volumes of the Michigan Series on the Middle East, the monthly Schedule of Events the Center has put out since 1989 and the Newsletter, among others. In the early 1990's, various faculty members wrote study and instruction guides entitled Roots of Violence in the Middle East for use in secondary schools.
Under Sub-Unit Publications are found another secondary-level study guide--produced by the Curriculum Development group. The publications of the nationwide Middle East Outreach Council, which is based at the Center, are also found in this series.
Topical Publications contains a study guide and various other research papers and programs published for seminars and workshops sponsored by the Center.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Center for Near Eastern & North African Studies.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs
Contributors:
University of Michigan. Center for Near Eastern & North African Studies.; Middle East Studies Association of North America.; Middle East Outreach Council
Genre/Form:
Calendars.; Newsletters.; Annual reports.; Reports.; Study guides.
- Unit Publications
  - Annual Reports
    - Final Performance Report, 1985/86-1993/94, 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Project Performance Report, 1994/95-1995/96 (Box 1)
  - Brochures
    - Center for Near/Middle Eastern and North African Studies, 1974/75-1994/95 (Box 1)
    - Master of Arts Program in Modern Middle Eastern and North African Studies, 1983/84-1996/97, undated (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1967-1985, undated (Box 1)
    - Near East and North Africa, 1964/65-1971/72 (Box 1)
  - Calendars
    - Schedule of Events, 1989-1999, 10 folders (Box 1)
  - Catalogs
    - Publications of the CNEA, 1967-1987 (Box 1)
  - Flyers, 1989-1998, 9 folders (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - Alumni Newsletter, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Newsletter, 1980-1999, 18 folders (Box 2)
  - Posters, 1984, undated (Box 2)
  - Reports
    - The Development Choices Model 1992 (Box 2)
      (with floppy disc for Lotus 1-2-3, v. 2.01)
    - Michigan Series on the Middle East
      - Nos. 1,2,4, 1989-1991 (Box 2)
  - Study Guides
    - Roots of Violence in the Middle East
      - Armed Rivalry in the Middle East, [1992] (Box 2)
      - Economic Inequality and Political Violence in the Middle East and North Africa, [1992] (Box 2)
      - Human Rights and Democratization in the Middle East, [1992] (Box 2)
      - The Israeli-Palestinian Conflict (2nd edition), 1993 (Box 2)
      - Religious Tensions in the Middle East, [1992] (Box 2)
      - Water Scarcity in the Middle East, [1992] (Box 2)
    - Women in the Middle East: A Handbook for Secondary Schools, [1993] (Box 2)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  - Curriculum Development Group
    - Study Guides
      - Petroleum and National Development in the Middle East: The Case of Saudi Arabia, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Middle East Outreach Council
    - Newsletters
      - Middle East Outreach Council Newsletter, 1994-1997 (Box 2)
  - Middle East Studies Association/Middle East Outreach Council
    - Reports
      - Evaluation of Secondary-Level Textbooks for Coverage of the Middle East and North Africa, 1994 (Box 2)
      - Middle East Studies Association/Middle East Outreach Council Text Evaluation Project, 1992 (Box 2)
- Topical Publications
  - Seminars
    - Global Education Through Literature and Art Teachers' Seminar
      - Study Guides
        - Beyond the Thousand and One Nights: A Sampler of Literature from Muslim Civilization, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Programs, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Workshops
    - Workshop Papers
      - Cases and Contexts in Islamic Law, 1994 (Box 2)